NATALY MENARES

(650) 250-6864 nataly.menares@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

SKILLS

More than 4 years working as a software engineer using frameworks **Ember.js** and **Vue.js**, with experience in **d3.js**, **jQuery**, **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **SQL**, **BigQuery**, **Firebase**, **Postgres**, and **Tableau**.

Basic knowledge in React.js, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Python, Google Analytics, and Google Cloud.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack - Software Developer (100% Remote)

MikMak, @New York, NY, US.

Jun 2021 - Jan 2023

- Lead and implement new features using **Vue.js** framework and other libraries like **d3.js** to create charts from scratch
- Work with REST APIs and queries (bigQuery and Postgres) to get information from databases.
- Code Jest unit-tests and dispatch and analyze logs on Amplitude and Datadog to debug, and understand product performance and user experience.

Frontend - Software Developer

Lore 10, @Sunnyvale, CA, US.

Jan 2019 - Jun 2021

- Design and develop new frontend features using **Ember.js** framework.
- Improve frontend application loading performance by 50% in the last year.
- Propose and implement UI/UX improvements.

Marketing Engineer - Remote (100% Remote)

<u>SimpliRoute</u>, @Providencia, Santiago, Chile.

Jan 2017 - May 2018

- Analyze market keywords to manage Adwords Campaigns and apply SEO techniques, resulting in 100% increase in demo requests within the first three months and reaching more than 300 new users monthly.
- Create Tableau dashboards to keep the company informed about marketing action-results.

Project Manager

Movistar, @Providencia, Santiago, Chile.

Aug 2015 - Sep 2016

- Manage Push Notification Advertising Campaigns, increasing related revenue by 500% through high quality data sets.
- Lead five projects at the same time, working side by side with technical teams from Telefonica and partner companies.
- Teach useful database skills and tools to colleagues to extract useful information about their projects and products.

Data Analyst

Movistar, @Providencia, Santiago, Chile.

Oct 2013 - Aug 2015

- Work side by side with three softwares developers and evidence (by experimental real time campaigns and data analysis) how important it was to build a Big Data area in the company.
- Work directly with Project and Product Managers to help them to get data and information to make relevant decisions about their projects.

PROJECTS

SomeWays Live Site | Github

JavaScript Project: Maze game, developed using JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3.

- Used HTML5 canvas to draw and manage the main elements of the game: maze and ball.
- Implemented a maze generation algorithm such that a user can move a ball through the maze.
- The maze is created using cell-logic inside a matrix. Once the first cell is chosen randomly -among a pull of available options- the other options are blocked, the new position is the chosen cell, and it is time to pick the next one,

repeating the process.

• Added different DOM Event listeners to simultaneously manage the one minute timer and the user's actions, such as ball movements and button inputs.

Knitting With Strangers

Live Site | Github

Full Stack clone of <u>Tea With Strangers</u> website with extra features, developed using Ruby for Backend and React-Redux for Frontend.

- Implemented CRUD API in Ruby on Rails to power the React frontend: Users can create a Knitting Time or book/cancel a spot in an existing one. Also, any Knitting Time can be updated or deleted by its host.
- Used React Router for seamless transitions between different sections of the site.
- Added modals using Redux to update Knitting Times description and view Host Profile.

EDUCATION

App Academy - Immersive software development course with focus on full stack web development (Summer 2018)

Universidad Diego Portales @Santiago, Chile - M.Sc - Marketing Management (2015 - 2017)

Universidad de Chile @Santiago, Chile - B.Sc. - Industrial Engineering (2006 - 2012)